Guide to the Lara Cohen Zine Collection, 1992-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lara Cohen Zine collection 1992-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cohen, Lara
9 linear feet Extent: 1000 Items
Lara Langer Cohen is an Assistant Professor in the Department of English at Wayne State University in Detroit, Michigan. She started collecting zines, including trading zines and corresponding with Sarah Dyer, in the early 1990s. The collection consists of approximately 280 zine titles (some with multiple issues) collected by Cohen and several hundred pieces of correspondence addressed to her or to her zines, Runt and Oh Oh Cheri, dating from the 1990s. Acquired by the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
RL.00242
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lara Cohen Zine Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2011.
Historical Note
Lara Langer Cohen is an Assistant Professor in the Department of English at Wayne State University in Detroit, MI. She started collecting zines, including trading zines and corresponding with Sarah Dyer, in the early 1990s.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of approximately 280 zine titles (some with multiple issues) collected by Cohen and several hundred pieces of correspondence addressed to her during the 1990s. The collection is arranged into two series: Zines and Correspondence. The zines have been divided into sub-series based on editorship by women, men, or both, and within each sub-series, alphabetized by title. The zines primarily focus on popular culture, opinion pieces, and music. Letters in the Correspondence Series are mostly addressed to "Lara" and "Runt," Cohen's zine, with standard mailing envelopes and self-made envelopes using re-purposed materials. The correspondence is arranged chronologically. Along with letters, the series includes postcards, greeting cards, flyers, photographs, and pamphlets. Most of the correspondence includes requests for zines or personal notes to Lara.
Acquired by the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Subject Headings
Cohen, Lara, collector; Comic books, strips, etc.; Young women -- Social life and customs; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Women's periodicals, American; Women poets; Sexual orientation; Feminism -- United States; Politics, Practical -- United States; Interpersonal relationships; Abused women; Fanzines; Fan magazines; Self-publishing; Underground press publications
Related Material
Other zine collections held by the Sallie Bingham Center include: the Sarah Maitland Zine Collection, the Arielle Greenberg Zine Collection, the Sarah Wood Zine Collection, and the Sarah Dyer Zine Collection.
Contents of Collection
- Zines, (8 boxes)
  The zines have been divided into sub-series based on editorship by women or men; zines are filed under women if they are co-edited and at least one editor is a woman. Within each sub-series, zines are alphabetized by title. Each folder contains an individual title with a range of issues included if known.
  - Zines Edited by Women
    - Absolute Beginners Club Social Handbook, Issue 1 (Box 1)
    - Action Girl Newsletter, Issues 2-9 and 12 (Box 1)
    - Action Teen, Issue 1 (Box 1)
    - Alien Girl (Box 1)
    - Baby, I Dig You, Issue 1 (Box 1)
    - Banana Split (France), Issue 1 (Box 1)
    - Basement Idyll (Japan), Issue 1 (Box 1)
    - Busy Bea's Bush, Issue 3 (Box 1)
    - Canadian Penny, Issues 1-7, and 9 (split issue with Agent Lame) (Box 1)
    - Catch That Beat! (Japan), Issue 7 (Box 1)
    - Chickfactor, Issues 2-12 (Box 1)
    - Coffee No Girl (Box 1)
    - Curiosity in Stout Shoes, Issue 1 (Box 1)
    - Curmudgeon, Issues 2-3 (Box 2)
    - Dirty Plotte, Issue 4 (Box 2)
    - Double Whammy, Issue 2 (Box 2)
    - Fast Connection, Issues 1-4 (Box 2)
    - Flatter, Issue 2 (Box 2)
    - Frantzine, Issues 4-5 (Box 2)
    - Free to Fight! (Box 2)
    - Girly Mag, Issues 1, 3-12 (Box 2)
    - Girly Magette (one and only) (Box 2)
    - Gloomy Biscuit (France), Issue 2 (Box 2)
    - Graham Cracker Cereal, Issue 1 (Box 2)
    - Heaven Sent (Box 2)
    - Hip Clown Rag, Issue 4 (Box 2)
    - Homocore NYC, Issue 4 (Box 2)
    - Honeysuckle, Issues 1-3 (Box 2)
    - I Wish I Was a Berrykin, Issue 3 (Box 2)
    - Kelp, Issues 4-5 (Box 2)
    - Kickstand, Issues 1 and 3 (Box 2)
    - Li'l Princess, Issue 2 (Box 2)
    - Linus Hates Me, Issue 2 (Box 2)
    - The Magazine of the Superdeformed World (Japan), Issue 2 (Box 2)
    - Meat Cake (comic), Issue 1 (Box 2)
    - Million Teddy Bears (Japan), Issue 1 (Box 2)
    - Mona, Issue 1-3 (Box 2)
    - Mudflap, Issues 5-6 (Box 3)
    - Nancy's Magazine (Box 3)
    - Non-Stop Diatribe, Issue 1 (Box 3)
    - Off the Road (Box 3)
    - Oh Oh Cheri, Issues 1-2 (Box 3)
    - Panophobia, Issues 2-5 (Box 3)
    - Pawholes, Issue 5 (Box 3)
    - Phonomania, Issue 3 (Box 3)
    - Pinto, Issues 5-6 (Box 3)
    - Popgirls, Issue 1 (Box 3)
    - Popka (mini-comic), Issue 1 (Box 3)
    - Power Toot, Issue 2 (Box 3)
    - Rabid, Issues 5-7 (Box 3)
    - Random Thoughts, Issues 2, 8-9 (Box 3)
    - Raspberry, Issues 3, 10 (Box 3)
    - Rollerderby, Issues 11-12 (Box 3)
    - Secret Weapon, Issue 3 (Box 3)
    - Septophilia catalog, Issue 2.5 (Box 3)
    - Sparkly Kitty Stickers, Issues 3-5 (Box 3)
    - Spelling, Issue 1 (Box 3)
    - Sprag, Issue 5 (Box 3)
    - Star Sign, Issue 3 (Box 3)
    - Stay Free, Issues 8, 10 (Box 3)
    - The Stomping Snooper (Box 3)
    - Sugar Rocket (Box 3)
    - Sunny Sundae Smile, Issue 3 (Box 4)
    - Superette, Issue 1 (Box 4)
    - Supergrowths (comic) (Box 4)
    - Swing If You're Glad to Be Girlie, Issue 1 (Box 4)
    - Teenage Gang Debs, Issues 2-5 (Box 4)
    - Topsy Turvy Twister Rama, Issues 1-2 (Box 4)
    - Totally Fucked, Issues 1-4 (Box 4)
    - Verboslammed, Issues 7, 9 (Box 4)
    - William Wants a Doll, Issue 3 (Box 4)
    - Wind-Up Butter Cow (Box 4)
    - Wind-Up Frozen Entree (Box 4)
    - Wind-Up Industrial Burnoff (Box 4)
    - Wind-Up State Souvenir Thimbles and Accoutrements (Box 4)
    - Wind-Up Toaster Pastry (Box 4)
    - Wind-Up Toy (Box 4)
  - Zines edited by men
    - A=1/f^2, Issue 1 (Box 4)
    - A Modern World, Issues 1-4 (Box 4)
    - Adventure Playground, Issue 3 (Box 4)
    - Amish ways, Issue 3 (Box 4)
    - Andy Remembers (mini-comic) (Box 4)
    - Bandits One to Five (Box 4)
    - Beer Frame, Issues 2-4 (Box 4)
    - Big Muff (Box 4)
    - Blaster, Issues 1-2, 4 (Box 4)
    - Bliss, Issues 1-2 (Box 4)
    - But the People Are Beautiful, Issue 1 (Box 4)
    - Caught in Flux, Issues 1-6 (Box 5)
    - Cheeseflower, Issue 1 (Box 5)
    - Chihuahua, Issues 6-8, 10 (Box 5)
    - Chivalry, Issues 1-2 (Box 5)
    - Chouette (Finland), Issue 1 (Box 5)
    - Clunker, Issues 1-2 (Box 5)
    - Circle, Issue 2 (Box 5)
    - Cool Beans!, Issue 3 (Box 5)
    - Dishwasher, Issue 11 (Box 5)
    - Duplex Planet, Issues 95-96, 100, 108, and special birthday issue for Simple Machines' Working Holiday series (Box 5)
    - Emily's Hip Pocket, Issues 5-6 (Box 5)
    - Eyes To See You With Make Me Look Elsewhere (mini-comic) (Box 5)
    - Fastidious Frog (mini-comic), Issue 1 (Box 5)
    - Fear and Loathing, Issue 33 (Box 5)
    - Feminist Baseball, Issues 13, 14, 14 1/4 (Box 5)
    - Fifteen (Box 5)
    - For Paper Airplane Pilots, Issues 1-4 (Box 5)
    - Frolic, Issues 1-5 (Box 5)
    - Gourmandizer (Box 5)
    - Heaven Sent, Issue 1 (Box 5)
    - Heinous, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - Hey Nineteen, Issues 1-2 (Box 6)
    - Incite!, Issues 25-27 (Box 6)
    - Kids in the Club, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - King-Kat Classix, Volumes 1-3 (Box 6)
    - King-Cat Comics, Issues 47, 49-50 (Box 6)
    - Kitty (Box 6)
    - Liontamer (Box 6)
    - Monk Mink Pink Punk, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - Mos Eisley, Issue 3 (Box 6)
    - Nib Comics, Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - No Duh (Box 6)
    - Noguchi's Hi-Fi (Box 6)
    - Nothing Doing, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - Objectified!, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - Open Your Eyes, Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - Pamfletti (Box 6)
    - Panegyric, Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - Paradiso (Box 6)
    - Phew! Wow!, Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - Positively Teenage (accompanies cassette compilation) (Box 6)
    - Quiet Nights of Quiet Stars (Box 6)
    - Runaway Balloon, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - Sarah newsletter, Issue 8 (Box 6)
    - Sarah obituary (Box 6)
    - Scrape, Issue 10 (Box 6)
    - Science Geek, Issues 1-2 (Box 6)
    - Secret Monkey Digest (Box 6)
    - Shinkansen newsletter, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - Sof' Boy (mini-comic), Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - Soft White Underbelly, Issue 3 (Box 6)
    - Some Hope and Some Despair, Issue 1 (Box 6)
    - Spam, Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - Sparky, Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - Speed Kills, Issue 2 (Box 6)
    - Spit and a Half (catalog), Issues 8-9, 12-13 (Box 6)
    - Splashdown, Issue 2 (Box 7)
    - Stop Messin' About (Box 7)
    - Sturgeon, Issue 2 (Box 7)
    - Sweet Portable You, Issue 76 (Box 7)
    - Take a Day, Issue 1 (Box 7)
    - This Almight Pop, Issues 1-4 (Box 7)
    - This Old Zine, Issues 1-3 (Box 7)
    - Thrill!, Issues 8-15, 17 (Box 7)
    - Tiger Lily (Box 7)
    - Trick Hips, Issue 2 (Box 7)
    - Two Pint Take Home!, Issue 1 (Box 7)
    - [Untitled] by Clint Barnes (Box 7)
    - Waaaaaa!, Issue 3 (Box 7)
    - What Did You Say?, Issue 1 (Box 7)
    - Whatever, Issue 2 (Box 7)
    - White Bread, Issues 9-10 (Box 7)
    - White Bread/Satanic Toasters split issue (Box 7)
    - Who Cares?, Issues 4 and 6 (Box 7)
    - Wig Out, Issue 21 (Box 7)
    - Wiggly Worms (comic) (Box 7)
    - Winky's Comics and Stories, Issues 1 and 3 (Box 7)
    - Woolly Bugger, Issues 1-2 (Box 7)
    - Woosh, Issues 2-3 (Box 7)
    - Writer's Block, Issues 7-8 (Box 7)
    - Yakuza, Issues 1-6, and mail order catalog (Box 7)
    - Yeast Hoist (mini-comic) (Box 7)
    - You Can't Be Loved Forever, Issue 2 (Box 7)
  - Other Zines, etc.
    - After Hours (Box 8)
    - An Introductory Mechanics Guide To Putting Out Records, Cassettes, and CDs (Box 8)
    - Autumn Smoke (Box 8)
    - Salive Blanquet (Box 8)
    - Soda for Girls, Issue 1 (Box 8)
    - Program for Yoyo A GoGo, 1994 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1992-1996, (6 boxes)
  Correspondence is arranged by month and year ranging between 1992-1996. Most material remains in its original envelope to preserve its context and original order. Items with no discernible "month" are foldered at the end of each year. Undated items are foldered at the end of the series. Series includes letters addressed to Lara Cohen or "Runt," her zine, as well as greeting cards, postcards, and photographs. There is also one folder of miscellaneous materials.
  - 1992, October to 1993, July (Box 9)
  - 1993, August to 1993, no month (Box 10)
  - 1994, January to 1994, April (Box 11)
  - 1994, May to 1994, August (Box 12)
  - 1994, August to 1995, May (Box 13)
  - 1995, June to 1996 (including undated items) (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 14)